Guide to the Charles Seymour Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- WRITINGS, 1918-(1924-1928)-1963; Series II; 13'9" (40 boxes)
  - Book Reviews
    - Five Weeks: The Surge of Public Opinion on the Eve of the Great War by Jonathan French Scott. Saturday Review of Literature (May 28, 1927). (Box 53, Folder 302)
    - The New Balkans by Hamilton Fish Armstrong, Forum (June 1927). (Box 53, Folder 303)
    - "Making the Peace." Saturday Review of Literature (July 2, 1927). A review of three books. (Box 53, Folder 304)
    - The World Crisis, 1916-1918 by Winston S. Churchill. Yale Review XVI, 4 (July 1927), pp. 789-781. (Box 53, Folder 305)
    - The Drafting of the Covenant by David Hunter Miller. Saturday Review of Literature V (October 13, 1928), p. 213. (Box 53, Folder 306)
    - War as an Instrument of National Policy and its Renunciation in the Pact of Paris by James T. Shotwell. Yale Law Journal (June 1929), pp. 1166-1168. (Box 53, Folder 307)
    - The Letters and Friendships of Sir Cecil Spring Rice. Edited by Stephen Gwynn. Yale Review XIX, 3 (March 1930), pp. 625-627. (Box 53, Folder 308)
    - Executive Agents in American Foreign Relations by Henry Merritt Wriston. Yale Law Journal (March 1930). (Box 53, Folder 309)
    - Grandeur and Misery of Victory by Georges Clemenceau. Saturday Review of Literature VI (April 19, 1930), pp. 939-940. (Box 53, Folder 310)
    - Austrian War Government by Joseph Redlich, Political Science Quarterly XLV, 4 (December 1930), pp. 604-606. (Box 53, Folder 311)
    - "Foch and Pershing." Yale Review XX, 4 (June 1931), pp. 805-809. A review of The Memoirs of Marshal Foch and My Experiences in the World War by John J. Pershing. (Box 53, Folder 312)
    - "Critical History of the World War." Yale Review XX, 2 (December 1930), pp. 388-391. A general review of four books. (Box 53, Folder 313)
    - The Coming of the War by Bernadotte E. Schmitt, Virginia Quarterly Review VII, 4 (October 1931), pp. 599-606. (Box 53, Folder 314)
    - The Epic of America by James Truslow Adams. Atlantic Monthly CXLVIII (November 1931), pp. 26-28. (Box 53, Folder 315)
    - "Wilson's Men." Atlantic Monthly CXLVIII (December 1931), pp. 20-22. A review of Crowded Years: Reminiscences of William G. McAdoo and Newton D. Baker at War by Frederick Palmer. (Box 53, Folder 316)
    - La Crise européene et la Grande Guerre, 1904-1918 by Pierre Renouvin. American Historical Review XL, 4 (July 1935), pp. 741-746. (Box 53, Folder 317)
    - Woodrow Wilson: Life and Letters, Vols. 3 and 4 by Ray Stannard Baker. New Republic LXIX (February 1932), pp. 327-328. (Box 53, Folder 318)
    - "Foch and Joffre." Yale Review XXI, 3 (March 1932), pp. 594-596. A review of Joffre by Raymond Recouly, and Foch: The Man of Orleans by B. H. Liddell Hart. (Box 53, Folder 319)
    - "Germany's Political System." Yale Review XXII, 1 (September 1932), pp. 170-172. A review of four books. (Box 53, Folder 320)
    - Woodrow Wilson: Life and Letters, Vols. 3 and 4 by Ray Stannard Baker. American Historical Review XXXVIII, 1 (October 1932), pp. 138-142. (Box 53, Folder 321)
    - Papers Relating to the Foreign Relations of the United States, 1917. Supplements 1 and 2, The World War. American Historical Review XXXIX, 1 (October 1933), pp. 149-152. (Box 53, Folder 322)
    - Our Times, Vol. 5: Over Here, 1914-1918 by Mark Sullivan. Saturday Review of Literature X (November 18, 1933), pp. 265-266. (Box 53, Folder 323)
    - "War and Peacemaking." Yale Review XXIII, 2 (December 1933), pp. 386-389. A review of War Memoirs of David Lloyd George, vols. 1 and 2, 1914-1916 and Peacemaking, 1919 by Harold Nicolson. (Box 53, Folder 324)
    - Peacemaking, 1919 by Harold Nicolson. Political Science Quarterly XLIX, 1 (March 1934), pp. 119-123. (Box 53, Folder 325)
    - Papers Relating to the Foreign Relations of the United States, 1918. Supplements 1 and 2, The World War 3 vols. Russia 3 vols. American Historical Review XXXIX, 3 (April 1934), pp. 549-551. (Box 53, Folder 326)
    - The Open Door at Home by Charles A. Beard. Current History XLI, 6 (March 1935), pp. 675-680. (Box 53, Folder 327)
    - Bliss, Peacemaker: The Life and Letters of General Tasker Howard Bliss by Frederick Palmer. Yale Review XXXIV, 3 (Spring 1935), pp. 626-628. (Box 53, Folder 328)
    - Road to War: America, 1914-1917 by Walter Millis. Yale Review XXIV, 4 (June 1935), pp. 833-836. (Box 53, Folder 329)
    - Journal d'Alexandre Ribot et Correspondence inédites, 1914-1922. Journal of Modern History (c. 1936). (Box 53, Folder 330)
    - Road to War: America, 1914-1917 by Walter Millis. Southwest Review XX (July 1935), pp. 1-6. (Box 53, Folder 331)
    - Woodrow Wilson: Life and Letters Vol. 5, by Ray Stannard Baker. Saturday Review of Literature XIII (December 7, 1935), pp. 5-6. (Box 53, Folder 332)
    - Lord Riddell's Intimate Diary of the Peace Conference and After, 1918-1923. American Historical Review XLI, 2 (January 1936), p. 385. (Box 53, Folder 333)
    - The Diplomacy of Imperialism, 1891-1902 by William Langer. Saturday Review of Literature XIII (February 22, 1936), p. 10. (Box 53, Folder 334)
    - The War Memoirs of Robert Lansing, Secretary of State by Robert Lansing. American Historical Review XLI, 3 (April 1936), pp. 561-563. (Box 53, Folder 335)
    - M-Day, The First Day of the War by Rose M. Stein. Saturday Review of Literature (April 4, 1936), pp. 39-40. (Box 53, Folder 336)
    - Les Délibérations du Conseil des Quatre (24 mars-28 juin 1919): Notes de l'Officier interprête by Paul Mantoux. American Historical Review LXI, 2 (January 1956), pp. 363-365. (Box 53, Folder 337)
    - Neutrality, Its History, Economics, and Law: Vol. III: The World War Period by Edgar Turlington. Georgetown Law Journal XXV, 2 (January 1937), pp. 505-507. (Box 54, Folder 338)
    - Memoirs of Count Bernstorff. Mississippi Valley Historical Review XXIII, 4 (March 1937), pp. 589-590. (Box 54, Folder 339)
    - Papers relating to the Foreign Relations of the United States, 1920. American Historical Review (January 1939), p. 401. (Box 54, Folder 340)
    - Papers Relating to the Foreign Relations of the United States, The Lansing Papers. Foreign Affairs Vol. 19 no. 2 (Jan 1941) pp. 414-425. (Box 54, Folder 340a)
    - Unfinished Business by Stephan Bonsal. American Foreign Service Journal XXI, (May 1944), pp. 249-250. (Box 54, Folder 341)
    - Woodrow Wilson and the Lost Peace by Thomas A. Bailey. Yale Review XXXIV, 1 (September 1944), pp. 158-160. (Box 54, Folder 342)
    - The Wilson Era: Years of War and After, 1917-1923 by Josephus Daniels. Virginia Quarterly Review XXII, 4 (Autumn 1946), pp. 611-613. (Box 54, Folder 343)
    - Wilson: The Road to the White House by Arthur Link. Virginia Quarterly Review XXIII, 4 (Autumn 1947), pp. 607-611. (Box 54, Folder 344)
    - A History of the League of Nations by F. P. Walters. Yale Review XLI, 4 (June 1952), pp. 609-611. (Box 54, Folder 345)
    - The Letters of Theodore Roosevelt, Vols. 1 and 2: The Years of Preparation. Edited by Elting E. Morison. Virginia Quarterly Review XXVII, 3 (Summer 1951), pp. 436-439. (Box 54, Folder 346)
    - The Political Collapse of Europe by Hajo Holborn. Yale Review XLI, 1 (September 1951), pp. 114-115. (Box 54, Folder 347)
    - The Letters of Theodore Roosevelt, Vols. 3 and 4: The Square Deal, 1901-1905. Edited by Elting E. Morison. Virginia Quarterly Review XXVIII, 1 (Winter 1952), pp. 147-151. (Box 54, Folder 348)
    - The Diplomats. Edited by Gordon A. Craig and Felix Gilbert American Historical Review LIX, 1 (October 1953), pp. 85-86. (Box 54, Folder 349)
    - The Letters of Theodore Roosevelt, Vols. 5 and 6: The Big Stick, 1905-1909. Edited by Elting E. Morison. Virginia Quarterly Review XXIX, 1 (Winter 1953), pp. 124-127. (Box 54, Folder 350)
    - The Letters of Theodore Roosevelt, Vols. 7 and 8: The Days of Armageddon, 1909-1919. Edited by Elting E. Morison. Virginia Quarterly Review XXX, 2 (Spring 1954), pp. 299-304. (Box 54, Folder 351)
    - Henry Cabot Lodge: A Biography by John A. Garrety. Yale Review XLIII, 2 (Winter 1954), pp. 273-274. (Box 54, Folder 352)
    - De la Nécessité d'une Conférence internationale sur le Coût de la vie (Box 54, Folder 353)
    - "Wilson Analyzed." Virginia Quarterly Review XXIV, 2 (Spring 1958), pp. 298-305. A general review of four books. (Box 54, Folder 354)
    - The Ordeal of Woodrow Wilson by Herbert Hoover. American Historical Review LVIV, 1 (October 1958), pp. 130-131. (Box 54, Folder 355)
    - Wilson: The Struggle for Neutrality, 1914-1915 by Arthur Link. Virginia Quarterly Review XXXVII, 1 (Winter 1960), pp. 142-145. (Box 54, Folder 356)
  - Lectures
    - Belgian lectures: pamphlet describing, 1924 (Box 55, Folder 357)
    - Belgian lectures: I. "Backgrounds,", 1924 (Box 55, Folder 358)
    - Belgian lectures: II. "Roosevelt and Hay,", 1924 (Box 55, Folder 359)
    - Belgian lectures: III. "Wilson and House,", 1924 (Box 55, Folder 360)
    - Belgian lectures: IV. "Wilsonian Policies", 1924 (Box 55, Folder 361)
    - Belgian lectures: V. "Principles and Methods,", 1924 (Box 55, Folder 362)
    - "European Personalities of the War" (Scranton Lecture), 1926 (Box 55, Folder 363)
    - "Personalities of the War" (Wallingford Lecture), 1927 (Box 55, Folder 364)
    - "R. S. Baker and the Speeding of the Treaties" (History Department Luncheon), Circa 1929 May (Box 55, Folder 365)
    - Albert Shaw Lectures on Diplomatic History (published as American Diplomacy During the World War ), 1933 (Box 55, Folder 366)
    - "House Collection" (Staff Lecture), 1935 (Box 55, Folder 367)
    - The Road to Peace: Nye Committee and American Neutrality, 1936 (Box 55, Folder 368)
    - "France at the Peace Conference" (Allison's Course), 1943 (Box 55, Folder 369)
    - Bowman Memorial Lecture: notes, [1951] (Box 55, Folder 370)
    - Bowman Memorial Lecture: notes and draft, [1951] (Box 55, Folder 371)
    - Bowman Memorial Lecture: "Geography, Justice, and Politics at the Peace Conference of 1919" (typescript and dictaphone recording), 1951 (Box 55, Folder 372)
    - Library Forum, 1952 (Box 55, Folder 373)
    - "Personal Aspects of Anglo-American Relations in the First World War" (Colby College Lecture), 1953 (Box 55, Folder 374)
    - Illustrations for Seminar, 1955 (Box 56, Folder 375-376)
    - Notes on House Collection, 1955 (Box 56, Folder 377)
    - "Realism and Idealism at Paris", (Bahlman - History 90 Seminar) (Box 56, Folder 378)
    - "The Role of Colonel House in Wilson's Diplomacy" (Indiana University), 1956 (Box 56, Folder 379)
    - "The Role of Colonel House in Wilson's Diplomacy" (Indiana University), 5 x 8 cards, 1956 (Box 56, Folder 380)
    - "The Role of Colonel House in Wilson's Diplomacy" (Indiana University), notes, 1956 (Box 56, Folder 381)
    - "Realism and Idealism at the Paris Peace Conference" (Bahlman Seminar), 1957 (Box 56, Folder 382)
    - "Wilson at Paris" (Choate Lecture), 1957 (Box 56, Folder 383)
    - Lamar - Bahlman Seminar, 1959 (Box 56, Folder 384)
    - "American Experts at the Paris Peace Conference,", undated (Box 56, Folder 385)
    - "Meetings of the Supreme Council", undated (Box 56, Folder 386)
  - Addresses
    - "Entrance Requirements and the College Curriculum", 1915 April 6 (Box 57, Folder 387)
    - "Aftermath of the Peace Conference" (Lyceum Club and Civitan Address), 1924 (Box 57, Folder 388)
    - Memorial Day Address, 1929 May 30 (Box 57, Folder 389)
    - Informal Address at Faculty Club, 1929 September 30 (Box 57, Folder 390)
    - Choate School Commencement Address, 1930 (Box 57, Folder 391)
    - Address at Alpha Delta Phi on House Plan, 1931 December 15 (Box 57, Folder 392)
    - Independence Day Address, 1935 July 4 (Box 57, Folder 393)
    - "The European Crisis" (Naval War College), 1935 September 27 (Box 57, Folder 394)
    - Yale Matriculation Address, 1937 October 4 (Box 57, Folder 395)
    - Inaugural Address, 1937 October 8 (Box 57, Folder 396)
    - "The University Curriculum in its Relation to Public Service" (Association of American Universities Conference), 1937 November (Box 57, Folder 397)
    - "Keeping the Peace" (under auspices of Yale Peace Council), 1938 April 23 (Box 57, Folder 398)
    - Address at Commemoration of First Meeting of General Court, 1938 June 6 (Box 57, Folder 399)
    - Address before Society of the Cincinnati, 1938 June 15 (Box 57, Folder 400)
    - Baccalaureate Address, 1938 June 20 (Box 57, Folder 401)
    - Harvard Commencement, 1938 June 23 (Box 57, Folder 402)
    - Yale Matriculation Address, 1938 October 2 (Box 57, Folder 402a)
    - Memorial Service for Prof. E.P. Morris, 1938 December 16 (Box 57, Folder 402b)
    - "The Treaty of Versailles", 1938 December 22 (Box 57, Folder 402c)
    - "University Organization", 1938 (Box 57, Folder 403)
    - Address to Headmasters, 1939 February 11 (Box 57, Folder 403a)
    - Summary of "The Price of American Security" (Yale Peace Council), 1939 May 18 (Box 57, Folder 403b)
    - "The Opportunity for a Liberal Education" (Thatcher School), 1939 May 21 (Box 57, Folder 403c)
    - Address at Wesleyan University upon receiving an honorary degree, 1939 June 18 (Box 57, Folder 403)
    - Address to Class of 1943, 1939 September 23 (Box 57, Folder 403e)
    - Address at "Fairfield Day," Fairfield, Conn., 1939 September 29 (Box 57, Folder 403)
    - Yale Matriculation Address, 1939 October 2 (Box 57, Folder 403g)
    - Address to Yale Corporation, 1939 October 14 (Box 57, Folder 403h)
    - Address to Alumnae of Vassar, 1939 October 21 (Box 57, Folder 403i)
    - Baccalaureate Address, 1939 (Box 57, Folder 403j)
    - Peace Council Address, [1939?] (Box 57, Folder 403k)
    - "Versailles Treaty and its Aftermath" (Yale Alumni Assoc. of Essex County, New Jersey), 1940 January 27 (Box 57, Folder 403l)
    - News Banquet, 1940 March 4 (Box 57, Folder 403m)
    - "The University" (University Dinner, University Club, New York), 1940 March 28 (Box 57, Folder 403n)
    - Baccalaureate Address, 1940 June 16 (Box 57, Folder 404)
    - Address at mass meeting called by Military Training Camps Association, 1940 June 17 (Box 57, Folder 404a)
    - Radio Address on behalf of the Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1940 June 22 (Box 57, Folder 404b)
    - "Responsibility and Privilege in a Democracy" (American College of Hospital Administration), 1940 September 15 (Box 57, Folder 404c)
    - Yale Matriculation Address, 1940 September 25 (Box 57, Folder 404)
    - Trumbull College Dinner (6 p.m. in the College Dining Hall), 1940 October 16 (Box 57, Folder 404e)
    - Address to New Haven Advertising Club Dinner for Dr. Verdi, 1940 November 12 (Box 57, Folder 404)
    - Address for Centenary of Congregation Mishkan Israel (New Haven), 1940 December 7 (Box 57, Folder 404g)
    - Address at Woolsey Hall, Yale, 1940 December 10 (Box 57, Folder 404h)
    - Address at New York Yale Club Council, and in Cleveland, 1941 January 21, 31 (Box 57, Folder 404i)
    - "University Ideals and Democracy", 1941 February 11 (Box 57, Folder 404j)
    - Alumni Day Address, 1941 February 22 (Box 57, Folder 404k)
    - Address for Greenwich, Conn., British War Relief, 1941 March 2 (Box 57, Folder 404l)
    - Baccalaureate Address, 1941 June 15 (Box 57, Folder 405)
    - Address at Dedication of Yale Medical Library, 1941 June 15 (Box 57, Folder 405a)
    - Alumni Luncheon Address, 1941 June 18 (Box 57, Folder 405b)
    - Address at Dedication of Hoover War Library, Stanford University, Calif., 1941 June 20 (Box 57, Folder 405c)
    - Chatham Broadcast, 1941 August 21 (Box 57, Folder 406)
    - Yale Matriculation Address, 1941 September 28 (Box 57, Folder 406a)
    - Yale Navy Day Address, 1941 October 28 (Box 57, Folder 406b)
    - Address to New Haven Advertising Club, 1941 November 17 (Box 57, Folder 406c)
    - Address to Yale Alumni University Fund Association (Yale Club, New York), [1941?] (Box 57, Folder 406)
    - Address at Dinner for Dr. Stanhope Bayne-Jones, 1942 January 14 (Box 57, Folder 406e)
    - Address at Dinner for Prof. Albert Galloway Keller (New Haven Lawn Club), 1942 January 17 (Box 57, Folder 406)
    - "Lessons of the Past Peace Conference" (International Students Meeting, Yale), 1942 February 1 (Box 57, Folder 406g)
    - News Banquet, 1942 February 16 (Box 57, Folder 406h)
    - "Yale's Job in This War" (Alumni Address), 1942 February 23 (Box 57, Folder 407)
    - Baccalaureate Address, 1942 June 7 (Box 57, Folder 407a)
    - Address for Andover, 1942 June 12 (Box 57, Folder 407b)
    - "Underlying Principles of a Peace Settlement" (Freshman Forum), 1942 July 31 (Box 57, Folder 407c)
    - Address to Freshman Class, 1942 October 2 (Box 57, Folder 407)
    - "Is Yale Going to Continue as a University in Time of War?,", 1942 December 8 (Box 57, Folder 407e)
    - Baccalaureate Address, 1942 December 19 (Box 57, Folder 407)
    - "Peacemaking in Light of the Versailles Treaty" (Columbia Faculty Club), 1943 November 4 (Box 57, Folder 408)
    - Baccalaureate Address, 1944 June 22 (Box 57, Folder 409)
    - "The School We've Handed On…", 1944 June 29 (Box 57, Folder 410)
    - Address at Institute of International Studies Dinner, 1945 February 8 (Box 58, Folder 411)
    - "The Problem of International Security: Historical Backgrounds" (Henry Wells Lawrence Memorial Lecture), 1945 February 27 (Box 58, Folder 412)
    - "The Coming Peace in the Light of Previous Failure", 1945 May 13 (Box 58, Folder 413)
    - "The United States' Foreign Policy" (Boston University Commencement), 1945 May 21 (Box 58, Folder 414)
    - Baccalaureate Address, 1945 June 22 (Box 58, Folder 415)
    - Yale Graduation Address, 1945 October 24 (Box 58, Folder 416)
    - "The First Mayor of Hartford", 1946 January 30 (Box 58, Folder 417)
    - Saybrook, First Church of Christ: 300th Anniversary, 1946 June 30 (Box 58, Folder 418)
    - Address of Institute of International Studies Dinner, 1946 December 12 (Box 58, Folder 419)
    - "Athletics at Yale" (Yale Club Dinner), 1946 December 17 (Box 58, Folder 420)
    - Address to American Philosophical Association, 1946 December 27 (Box 58, Folder 421)
    - Clark University - Inauguration of President Howard Jefferson, 1947 February 1 (Box 58, Folder 422)
    - Baccalaureate Address, 1947 June 15 (Box 58, Folder 423)
    - "The Problem of Compromise" (Baccalaureate Address), 1947 June 16 (Box 58, Folder 424)
    - "Greetings" (100th Anniversary of Sheffield Scientific School), 1947 October (Box 58, Folder 425)
    - "A Sense of Perspective" (Graduation), 1948 February 6 (Box 58, Folder 426)
    - Address of Presentation of the Statue of Nathan Hale to the Nation, 1948 April 18 (Box 58, Folder 427)
    - "To Listen and to Inquire" (Baccalaureate Address), 1948 June 20 (Box 58, Folder 428)
    - "Yale Presidents of the Past" (Yale Club Council Dinner), 1948, 1949 (Box 58, Folder 429)
    - "Live Magnanimously" (Baccalaureate Address), 1949 June 19 (Box 58, Folder 430)
    - "Responsibilities of an Educated American" (Des Moines), 1949 October 19 (Box 58, Folder 430a)
    - "Problems of University Administration", 1949 November (Box 58, Folder 431)
    - "Yale: From Collegiate School to University" (Yale Club Council Dinner), 1949 December 27 (Box 58, Folder 432)
    - Yale Daily News Dinner, 1950 February 8 (Box 58, Folder 433)
    - Alumni Address, 1950 June 19 (Box 58, Folder 434)
    - "Tradition of the Liberal Arts College" (Middlebury College Sesquicentennial), 1950 September 29 (Box 58, Folder 435)
    - Baccalaureate Address - University of Connecticut, 1951 June 10 (Box 58, Folder 436)
    - Alumni Address, 1951 June 17 (Box 58, Folder 437)
    - "Traditional Values of Yale College" (Aurelian Society), 1951 December 11 (Box 58, Folder 438)
    - Reunion Address - Class of 1926, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 439)
    - "Corporation", 1952 May 16 (Box 58, Folder 440)
    - Alumni Address, 1952 June 15 (Box 58, Folder 441)
    - Berkeley Senior Dinner (not delivered), 1953 May 13 (Box 58, Folder 442)
    - Alumni Address, 1953 June 14 (Box 58, Folder 443)
    - "Academic Freedom Means Academic Responsibility" (WTIC Radio), 1953 June 14 (Box 58, Folder 444)
    - Alumni Address, 1954 June 13 (Box 58, Folder 445)
    - Yale Club of New York, 1954 December 28 (Box 58, Folder 446)
    - "Yale Residential Colleges", 1956 November 2 (Box 58, Folder 447)
    - "Woodrow Wilson: A Political Balance Sheet" (American Philosophical Society), 1956 November 15 (Box 58, Folder 448)
    - Address at Memorial Service of George H. Townsend, 1957 March 2 (Box 58, Folder 449)
    - "Timothy Dwight", 1957 [?] (Box 58, Folder 450)
    - Alumni Luncheon Address, 1958 June 15 (Box 58, Folder 451)
    - Address at Yale, 1960 February 12 (Box 58, Folder 451a)
    - Address to Reunion of Class of 1935, 1960 June 17 (Box 58, Folder 452)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Sonnett, 1901 (Box 59, Folder 452a)
    - "The Development of Democracy in England Since 1832: As Shown in the Reform of the Representation System" (Yale Ph.D. dissertation), 1911 May (Box 59, Folder 452b)
    - "The Development of Democracy in England Since 1832: As Shown in the Reform of the Representation System," bibliography and appendices, 1911 May (Box 59, Folder 452c)
    - American Diplomacy, outlines and notes, 1923 (Box 59, Folder 453)
    - "War Diplomacy," outlines and drafts, 1931 (Box 59, Folder 454)
    - "Reveries of a Banker Embarking on his Holiday", 1933 April 25 (Box 59, Folder 454a)
    - Cambridge Modern History. New Series. Chapter XXVI: "Diplomatic History of the War," ii: "Peace Movements," first draft, 1939 (Box 59, Folder 455)
    - Notes on "Background of Yale Med. School", 1940 October 28-30 (Box 59, Folder 455a)
    - "Comments on the Yale Colleges, 1928-1948," (Box 59, Folder 455b)
    - European Diplomacy After 1914, outlines, undated (Box 59a, Folder 456)
    - The United States Since 1914 ("Nations of Today" series), incomplete manuscript, undated (Box 59a, Folder 457)
    - Miscellaneous notes and drafts, undated (Box 59a, Folder 458)
    - The Origin of the Dawes Plan, undated (Box 59a, Folder 459)
    - Notecards, undated (Box 59a, Folder 460)
- TOPICAL FILES, 1916-(1918-1919)-1959; Series III; 2 linear feet (8 boxes)
  This series is divided into two sections:
  Peace Conference (4 boxes)
  This section contains miscellaneous informational material utilized by Seymour in his various capacities as a territorial expert attached to the American Commission to Negotiate Peace at the Paris Peace Conference in 1919. The material begins with the "Black Book" containing the Inquiry's recommendations and reports to President Wilson and the Plenipotentiaries. This is followed by the chronologically arranged reports of meetings of the Commission for the Study of Territorial Questions Relating to Roumania and Jugo-Slavia. Next are reports and data pertaining to areas under consideration by the Commissioners, arranged in alphabetical order by country. At the end of the section are miscellaneous bulletins, summaries, memoranda, and maps.
  General (2 boxes)
  This section contains miscellaneous notes, articles by other people, biographies, and Congressional Record reprints which were useful to Seymour in researching his books and articles. The material is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  History Department (2 boxes)
  This section consists of history papers written by Seymour's students, attendance and grade books, and a small amount of history department administrative papers. The grade books and administrative papers will be closed to research until 2009.
  - Peace Conference
    - Black Book I: Outline of Tentative Report and Recommendations For the President and Plenipotentiaries, 1919 January 21 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Commission for the Study of Roumanian Territorial Questions
      - Session 1, 1919 February 8 (Box 60, Folder 2)